MICHAEL HUCKEBY

10118 N. 84th W. Ave, Sperry, OK 74073

(918) 319-1066

MichaelHuckeby41@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Security Professional | Military Veteran with an active Security Clearance and 7 years as a proven leader and manager able to multi – task missions, projects, and programs placing the right personnel and resources as needed to meet internal and external suspense's; depth of experience leading teams of teams. Possesses extensive background in security operations, composite risk management, emergency response, and chain of custody reporting practices. Accustomed to handling sensitive, confidential records with professionalism and desecration. Demonstrated history of producing accurate and timely products and possesses an innate talent for quickly mastering technology and new concepts. Critical and analytical, identified crucial corporate shortfalls; worked tirelessly identifying, appropriating and applying techniques, identified as corporate best practices. Career supported by specialized military leadership training and a Bachelor of Science in International Relations, Minor in Intelligence Studies – Certification in Terrorism Studies.

- Cross Functional Leadership
- Qualitative Assurance
- Data Analysis
- •

Project Management

- Composite Risk Management
- Policy Implementation
- Strategic Planning & Forecasting
- Force Protection
- Operations / Information Security

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CONSTELLIS NATIONAL SECURITY | ACADEMI, LLC – Kabul, Afghanistan

2016 -

Present

Security Contractor, Special Missions Wing

Managed all aspects of base security operations for the Special Operations Command in Afghanistan. Oversaw High Value Executive Protection on DOD and OGA facilities spanning more than 1K personnel and more than \$25M worth of equipment.

- Member of "Set Up" Team, wrote standard operating procedures, developed battle rhythms, and created training
 practices to initialize the contract with Guardian Angel | PSD of the Special Missions Wing Compound
 - Developed security measures tailored towards U.S. Special Operation Forces, Afghan Special Forces, Afghan Commandos, and Afghan Special Missions Wing
 - Created the base security plan, implemented protocols for base defense and complex attacks to include emergency response
- Maintained accountability of \$3.2M worth sensitive and serialized equipment at a 99.2% serviceability readiness
- Provided Operations Security training and briefings to 300+ personnel emphasizing the importance of protecting sensitive information; decreased the occurrence rate of security incidents by 80%
- Led readiness training drills in categories including: emergency response, active shooter, first responder, and base security actions
- Mobile Escort | Roving Patrol
 - o Planned routes, ensured clearance, and accompanied VIP guest throughout visits

TULSA COUNTY SHERIFFS OFFICE – Tulsa, OK

2014

-2016

Violent Crimes Task Force Officer

Police Officer assigned to the Tulsa County Drug | Violent Crimes Task Force. Primary worked undercover to discover and uncover illegal drug operations in the region and throughout the country. Coordinated, managed, and participated in undercover narcotics operations leading to properly prepared cases for successful prosecution in court.

- SWAT | Special Operations Team Member
 - Collaborated on 30+ missions with the FBI Joint Terrorism Task Force, DEA, Oklahoma Bureau of Narcotics, and FBI Street Crimes Unit
 - Delivered high risk search warrants; participated in buy busts, buy walks, surveillance and intelligence gathering operations
 - Oversaw all tactical operations, tactical response, special operations training, and policies
- Developed sources of information; located and interviewed confidential informants maintained the
 personal safety for 3-5 informants at any time
- Briefed agency leadership on status reports routinely; led a 4 person operating performing extensive drugs sting operations

MICHAEL HUCKEBY, Pg. 2

Violent Crimes Task Force Officer (Conti.)

- Extensive training in undercover operations to include: Close Quarters room clearing, search warrant delivery techniques, convoy operations, and advanced arrest techniques
- Expert Qualifications: Standard Issued Glock, AR-15/M-4, Shotgun, M-4, blackout pistols, shotguns, pepper ball guns, surveillance and counter surveillance techniques, etc.

GARY GLANZ & ASSOCIATES - Oklahoma

Part-Time Security Contractor

Provided independent security for various corporate, community, and private events to include: personal security, concert security, and political event security.

- 3 years working with entertainers (actors/actresses/musicians) ensuring force protection measures were implemented and enforced on sets and during concerts maintained riot control of crowds surpassing 50K
- Provided 24/7 security for Board Members during board meetings regarding sensitive voting

Additional Law Enforcement History

| 2013 - 2014 | Drug Interdiction Officer | Skiatook Police Department, Skiatook, OK |
|-------------------------|-------------------------------------|--|
| 2012 - 2013 | Police Officer | Eufaula Police Department, Eufaula, OK |
| 2010 – 2012 City, OK | Police & Entry Response Team Member | Oklahoma Department of Corrections, Oklahoma |

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

OKLAHOMA NATIONAL GUARD - Oklahoma City, OK

2009

- 2015

Infantry Operations Leader

Assisted senior managers and mid - managers in planning and preparation of combat missions; advised on directives | initiatives in support of a 40+ personnel platoon ensuring safety and mission success were achieved; maintained \$5M in tactical vehicles and sensitive equipment. 45th Infantry Brigade

- Managed the professional growth and counseling of 5 personnel daily; resulted in quarterly and yearly evaluation reports, career development charts and mentorship counseling
- Authored 35 operational plans at the strategic level, managing the execution of the plans at the tactical level, and monitoring the outcomes to ensure achievement and organizational goals
- · Developed and prioritized management interventions and training recommendations to mitigate potential risks and

negative impacts

- Established proactive management techniques to achieve organizational objectives by developing and updating standard operating procedures
- Managed the accountability and maintenance of \$5M in organizational equipment with zero loss; resulted in a 9% reduction of fraud, waste and abuse while successfully repairing damaged equipment to free up 26% of the annual budget
- Developed and instructed classes to promote effective public relations to include; key leader engagements, actions on the objective, and effective partnership
- Planned and executed recon missions in order to develop analysis reports on terrain features, enemy strength, disposition, and equipment
- Expert Qualifications: M-4, M-16, .50Cal, M240B, M249, MK-19

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelors of Science in International Relations, Minor in Intelligence Studies – Certification in Terrorism Studies

American Military University (in pursuit)

Police (CLEET) | Certified Entry Response Team (CERT) #132369 State of Oklahoma, Council on Law Enforcement Education and Training

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software: Microsoft Office (2003, 2007, 2010, 2013)

Access, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, OneNote, Outlook, Project, Publisher, Visio, InfoPath, SharePoint, Adobe Suite

Operating Systems: Mac / Microsoft Windows (95, 98, XP, Vista), Windows 10